# **David Ray Riley**

# Full Stack Net Developer

☑ crazycoding330@gmail.com 📞 +1 781 530 4078 😲 Weatherford, TX 🕡 https://github.com/topten1004

https://davidprofile.on.fleek.co in linkedin.com/in/david-riley-49045a266/

### **Profile**

8+ years of experience in Software Application Development. Application development using with C#, WCF, WPF and Win forms. Expert at Frontend frameworks such as React, Angular and Vue.JS. Good knowledge to web Technologies: ASP.NET, Node.JS, ASP.NET core. Experience with Trello, Github, GitLab, Azure DevOps, Agile and CI/CD. Ability to learn & develop using new technologies quickly. Highly motivated, quick learning team player with good technical skills. Coordinating with the team and with client.

## **Education**

**Bachelor Degree Texas State University** 

04.2010 - 04.2014San Marcos, United States

# **Professional Experience**

### **Lead Net Developer** Tesora International 7

07.2020 - 12.2022

- Developed frontend using Angular and admin-panel using React.
- Used Redux(Thunk) and Ngrx for the flex pattern and selected Tailwind CSS and Styled Components for CSS framework.
- Added mint, transfer logic with Smart contract base on ERC721 with Solidity using Truffle.
- Created RESTful endpoints using Asp.net Core Web API and PostgreSQL.
- Used FluentValidation, Cronos, Nethereum and Swashbuckle packages for backend development.
- Hosted backend using AWS Elastic Beanstalk and set CI/CD on the Azure DevOps.
- Implemented Microservice to the backend and divided into 3 main logic services.
- Implemented SSO using own company's third party API and used OpenId.
- Using IPFS and infra for NFT minting and implemented auction, bid, create and offer login in backend.
- Developed Restful APIs using Symphony backend and integrated with Vue.js frontend.

# Full Stack Net Developer TePe USA

11.2018 - 06.2020

- Used React JS for creating reusable UI components and have chosen Material UI for CSS styling.
- Implemented Redux(Thunk) for the frontend to control the state and used TypeScript.
- Implemented Auth0 and html2canvas package for the frontend
- Created Menus and Drawer component by using Typescript.
- Analyzed code quality and performance with jsHint and YSlow.
- Frontend project hosting using Digital Ocean and set CI/CD on the Azure DevOps.
- Implemented Repository pattern to the backend and follow code-first design and Domain Driven Design.
- Implemented Swashbuckle nuget package for SwaggerUI for API.
- Using GraphQL and used xUnit and nUnit for test case using Moq.

# ASP.NET MVC Developer Bell Boy Room Service

04.2017 - 09.2018

- Developed frontend using Angular, HTML/CSS/JavaScript and JQuery.
- Used code-first design pattern and EF6.0, Firebase, MS SQL Server for database management.
- Implemented real time chat server for chat and used MVVM pattern for backend development.
- Used repository pattern and microservice for backend development and used LINQ.
- Used Twilio, Smtp nuget package for client service and swashbuckle.
- Integrated Payment process with bank account and use Stripe API.
- Followed SDLC for development and xUnit, nUnit for test cases.
- Divided backend into 3 logic layers so users can use backend easily.
- Used Twilio package for sending SMS and LinqToExcel, Syncfusion UI for the document printing.
- Used CQRS, MediatR and Domain Driven Design pattern for the backend development to optimize the speed of the project.

### NET Developer Dorm Mom

09.2014 - 02.2017

- Collaborating with the project manager, business analysts, and other stakeholders to define the system requirements, features, and functionalities of the LMS.
- Designing the system architecture and database schema, ensuring scalability, security, and performance.
- Implementing the user interface (UI) using Asp.net MVC, HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Developing the backend services and APIs using C#, .NET Framework, and Entity Framework.

### **Skills**

#### **Frontend**

Angular/Angular.JS Razor React.JS Redux/Ngrx/Vuex

#### **UI Frameworks**

Ant Design Bulma Material UI Tailwind CSS Dev Express Kendo Telerik

#### Backend

Node.JS Laravel Django Spring Boot

#### **NET Side**

ASP.NET Core ASP.NET Web API ASP.NET MVC Blazor

#### **Mobile & Desktop**

WCF WPF MAUI Xamarin/React Native/Flutter

#### **Database**

MS SQL Server MongoDB MySQL Oracle PostgreSQL

#### **Tools**

AWS Service
Azure DevOps
Docker
Github
Gitlab
Visual Studio
Visual Studio Code
Trello

- Integrating third-party tools and plugins such as payment gateways, video hosting services, and analytics platforms.
- Testing the system features and functionalities using unit testing, integration testing, and acceptance testing.
- Deploying the system to the production environment using Azure DevOps and Azure App Service.
- Providing technical support and maintenance to the system users, troubleshooting issues, and fixing bugs.

## **Projects**

#### 07.2020 - 12.2022

# Tesora International Lead Net Developer

- Implemented microservice to the backend and used Npgsql for postgreSQL database.
- https://github.com/TopTen1004/Tesora-Backend
- Developed frontend using React, Redux(Thunk), Ngrx(Rxjs) and Styled Components.
- https://github.com/TopTen1004/Tesora-Frontend
- https://www.tesora.art/
- This is my latest ASP.NET Core web API endpoints hosted on AWS.
- http://nftdatabase-dev.us-west-2.elasticbeanstalk.com/swagger/index.html
- Implemented Microservice, Domain Driven Design, DI and Repository Pattern.

#### 11.2018 - 06.2020

#### TePe USA r?

### **Full Stack .Net Developer**

- Developed backend using Repository pattern and implemented Code First, Domain Driven Design, T-SQL.
- https://github.com/TopTen1004/TePe-API
- Developed frontend using React(TypeScript), Material UI, Redux, Hooks and WireFrame to control the canvas.
- https://github.com/TopTen1004/TePe-Frontend
- https://www.tepe.com/global/

#### 04.2017 - 09.2018

# Bell Boy Room Service ♂ ASP.NET MVC Developer

- Used Asp.Net MVC and Asp.Net web api for the project
- Follow the SDLC and Implemented microservice and Domain Driven Design.
- https://app.bell-boy.com/
- https://github.com/TopTen1004/App-Bell-Boy